Guide to the Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics, 1970s-1990s LATINAMER.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Latin American Countries, I.
  - Nicaragua, 9.
    - Edward S. Herman. Objective News as Systematic Propaganda: The NYT on the 1984 Salvadoran and Nicaraguan Elections of 1984, Covert Action Information Bulletin, Spring 1984 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Marc Edelman, Soviet-Nicaraguan Relations and the Contra War North American Congress on Latin America (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Nicaragua-The Counterrevolutionary Plan of the U.S. in Action. John Foran and Jeff Goodwin, Revolutionary Outcomes in Iran and Nicaragua: Coalition Fragmentation, War, and the Limits of Social Transformation (Paper prepared for delivery at the Annual Meeting of the American Sociological Association), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Nicaraguan Army Contains Counterrevolutionary Operation Prensa Latina, Managua, February 9, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - John Gitlitz, Critique of State Department Report on Human Rights Practices in Nicaragua (Unpublished paper) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - U.S. Citizens Repudiate Travel Advisory Against Nicaragua (Issued by the Committee of U.S. Citizens Living in Nicaragua), February 4, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - United Nations General Assembly, Thirty-sixth Session, General Assembly Provisional Verbatim Record of the Twenty-Ninth Meeting (Contains the address by Daniel Ortega, original text of speeches delivered in English and interpretations of speeches in other languages), October 8, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Ruben Berrios and Marc Edelman, Hacia la Diversificacion de la Dependencia, Los Vinculos Economicos de Nicaragua con los Paises Socialistas Comercio Exterior, Vol. 35 (10) Mexico. Oct. 1985: 998-1006, October 1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - United States Congress, Congressional Record Who Are the Contras? Proceedings and Debates of the 99th Congress, First Session, April 23, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Presbyterian Church in the United States, Reports to the 1983 General Assemblies Part IV, Atlanta, Georgia, June 1983 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Nicaragua in the New World (Dis) Order: 'Free Trade' Liberalism, Security and the Crisis of Development (blind review manuscript), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Sandra Dickson, Press and U.S. Policy Toward Nicaragua, 1983-1987: A Study of the New York Times and Washington Post Journalism Quarterly, Autumn 1992 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - W. Lance Bennett, Toward a Theory of Press-State Relations in the United States Journal of Communication, Spring 1990 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - La Asamblea Nacional de la Republica de Nicaragua, Legalizacion de Viviendas y Terrenos: El Presidente de la Republica de Nicaragua Hace Saber al Pueblo Nicaraguense que: (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - La Asamblea Nacional de la Republica de Nicaragua, Ley de Transmision de Viviendas Estatales: Ley No. 85 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Acuerdos de la Segunda Fase de la Concertacion Economica y Social, August 13, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Xavier Campos, Ruben Ardila Gomez, Sandino (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Thomas Walker, Nicaragua: Catholic Unity Dissolves in Revolutionary Nicaragua, Mesoamerica, September 1982 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - W. Dean Hopkins, A Consideration of How the U.S. Media Inform, Misinform, and Fail to Inform, with the Nicaraguan Election as a Primary Election (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - John Meehan, Memorandum to Mr. J. Peter Grace, RE: Archbishop of Managua, Nicaragua (F.Y.I. Copy), May 9, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Pablo Antonio Vega, Bishop, Bishop Vega's remarks at International Press Club in Managua, Nicaragua, July 2, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Contadora Primer, International Policy Report, September 1986 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Catherine Gander, Nicaragua (Unpublished paper) (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Joel Millman, Narco-terrorism: A Tale of Two Stories, Columbia Journalism Review, September-October 1986 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Philippe Bourgois, The Miskitu of Nicaragua: Politicized Ethnicity, Anthropology Today, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Permanent Mission to the United Nations, Republic of Nicaragua, Text of Note from H.E. Ambassador Alejandro Bendana, Alternative Permanent Representative of Nicaragua to the United Nations, January 11, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Javier Chamorro Mora, (Nicaraguan Ambassador to UN), Letter to UN Secretary General Javier Perez de Cuellar, January 6, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Robert Parry and Brian Barger, Reagan's Shadow CIA: How the White House Ran the Secret 'Contra' War, The New Republic, November 24, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Nicaragua: Abuses By All Sides, Human Rights Watch, March 1986 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Andrew Reding, Tomas Borge Talks About the Revolution, In These Times, September 18-24, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Joyce Heard and Joan Kruckewitt, How Washington's Allies Are Aiding the Sandinistas, Business Week, July 29, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Mario Vargas Llosa, In Nicaragua, The New York Times Magazine, April 28, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Edgar Chamorro, The Contras Were Bom In Original Sin, In These Times, September 4-10, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Michael Robins, et al., PEPP 1986-87 Funding Proposal, Popular Participation Studies Program (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - James Chace, Dithering in Nicaragua, The New York Review, August 17, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - James E. Austin and John C. Ickis, Management, Managers, and Revolution, World Development, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Taking Care of Business in Nicaragua, Multinational Monitor, April 1985 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Why A Solution Based on International Law Is Ignored, Nicaragua in Brief, July 16, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Testimony of Father Miguel D'Escoto (Press Release), July 8, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Nicaraguan Reply to Contra Vote (Press Release), July 14, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Nicaragua Warns of United States Interference in the Inter-American Development Bank, Nicaragua in Brief, March 29, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Sincere Negotiations: Respect for Law and Self-Determination, Nicaragua in Brief, March 14, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Statement (Press Release), February 7, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Peace Through Respect for Law, Nicaragua in Brief, December 4, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, At the Crossroad of Peace or War, Nicaragua in Brief, August 13, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Embassy to the United States of the Republic of Nicaragua, Official statement of the government of Nicaragua regarding reports published in the U.S. press with respect to the alleged introduction of MIG aircrafts into Nicaragua (Press Release), November 7, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Miguel Angel Casco, Mensaje de CEPRES en la Apertura de las Primera Asamblea de Evangelicos Intergrados en los Diversos Organismos de la Revolucion, July 12, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Information and Disinformation, Central American Network Newsletter (CANN), April 1986 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Documents and Readings of the LASA Delegation (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Universidad Nacional Agraria UNA (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - United States Government, House of Representatives, House Resolution 4404, May 1,1990 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - United Nations, Security Council, United Nations Observer Group in Central America: Report of the Secretary General, June 29,1990 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - United Nations, Security Council, United Nations Observer Group in Central America: Report of the Secretary General, March 15, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Jack Child, ed., Notes from June 1991 Nicaragua Trip, 15-27, June 1991. 530. Attacks by the Nicaraguan Contras on the Civilian Population of Nicaragua, March 1985 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Consejo Universitario de la UNAN-LEON, A La Comunidad Universitaria, Padres de Familia y Pueblo Nicaraguense: (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - CIAV OEA Nicaragua, June 24, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Anos de Lucha por la Paz y la Soberania (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - The Limits of Popular Revolutionary Democracy: Nicaragua's Transition from Authoritarian Rule (manuscript for blind review for Comparative Politics, 1992) (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Amnesty International, Nicaragua Background Briefing: Persistence of Public Order Law Detentions and Trials, December 30, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Amnesty International, Update to Amnesty International's Report, Torture in the Eighties: Nicaragua, Amnesty International News Release, May 30, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Report Documenting Numerous Attacks on Civilians by Contras in Nicaragua Released at News Conference, March 7, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - David C. MacMichael, Summary of Observations of the Nicaraguan Elections, November 4, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - William R. Callahan, The Nicaraguan Elections: A Special Report, January 1985 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - United Nations, International Court of Justice, Affidavit of Edgar Chamorro, (Nicaragua v. United States of America), September 5, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - FSLN Foreign Relations, Communique: Operacion Naivdad Roja, February 5, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Daniel Ortega Saavedra, Communique of the Government of Nicaragua, April, 12, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Primera Fase de la Concertacion Economica y Social (1990 or 1991) (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Los Nueve Puntos de lo Siete Partidos, Letter to President Daniel Ortega from the seven political parties, February 5, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Velasquez, Liliana. Fidel Castro and the Sandinistas: A Dangerous Relationship? (Paper presented in the Latin American Seminar, Spring 1993, Ohio University) (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Goodfellow, William C. Prepared Statement of William C. Goodfellow, Executive Director of the Center for International Policy Before the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, Thursday, February 4, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Helms, Jesse. Not Another Cent For Nicaragua Congressional Record - Senate, April 2,1993 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Hossie, Linda. Working to Restore Full Aid to Nicaragua The Globe and Mail, March 5, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Cullum, Elyse. Evangelical Protestants in Nicaragua: An Examination of their Influence During the 1980s Paper presented in Latin American Studies, Ohio University, June 1993 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Scruggs, T.M. Country Profile: Nicaragua. UNESCO Universe of Music Encyclopedia, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Articles on Assassination of Anastasio Somoza Debayle appeared in Barricada, Summer 1993 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Van Rossem, Elizabeth. The Role of the United States in the 1984 Nicaraguan Elections Paper presented in the Seminar in Latin America, Ohio University, Spring 1993 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Cullum, Elyse. U.S. and Contadora (Paper presented at Ohio University), Summer 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ec. Committee of U.S. Church Personnel in Nicaragua. Continuing the Disinformation Campaign: The Tragic Events in Esteli, Summer 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Armony, Ariel C. Argentina and the Origins of Nicaragua's Contras, in Low Intensity Conflict & Law Enforcement, vol. 2, no. 3, Winter 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - CENPAP. Informe De Actividades, November 1991 (Contras) (In Spanish) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - CENPAP. Analisis de la Situacion de los Problemas Agrarios - Se Profundizan las Tensiones Agrarias (Tension in el Campo), April 28, 1991 (Contras) (In Spanish) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - CENPAP. Informe Evaluativo de las Actividades Realizadas por el CENAP- Septiembre 1990-Septiembre 1992, Managua, November, 1992 (Contras) (In Spanish) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - CENPAP. Situacion Socio-Economica Actual Y Necesidades Materiales Y Financieras Para el Desarrollo Productivo de los Desmovilizados de la Resistencia Nicaraguense, Managua, July 17, 1992 (Contras) (In Spanish) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - CENPAP. La Reforma Agraria Y los Polos de Desarrollo - Estudio Basico de las Fincas Distribuidas a los Desmovilizados de la Resistencia Nicaraguense, January 1992 (Contras) (In Spanish) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Messina, Sonia V. How Negotiations Were Shut Down (The Politics of U.S.- Nicaraguan Negotiations, 1981-1984), POLS 590 Iran-Contra Affairs, Ohio University, March 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Revolution Continues: Women's Organizing and Democracy in Nicaragua (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Source: MCE. Nicaragua The Economy in Graphics, includes official statistics up to 1994 in some graphs (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Prevost, Gary. The Nicaraguan Revolution - Four Years After The Sandinista Electoral Defeat, Prepared for delivery at the LASA, XVIII International Congress, Atlanta, GA (Preliminary Draft - Not To Be Quoted or Cited), March 10-12, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Williams, Philip J. Dual Transitions from Authoritarian Rule - Popular and Electoral Democracy in Nicaragua, in Comparative Politics, January 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Spalding, Rose J. Democratic Governance in Nicaragua. Prepared for delivery at the 1994 Meeting of the North American Society for Social Philosophy, New York, New York, September 1-4, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Anderson, Leslie. Neutrality and Bias in the 1990 Nicaraguan Pre-Electoral Polls, copy of article to appear in AJPS, May 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean. Nicaragua: An Economy in Transition, May 31, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Craven, David. Manuscript text on Art in Nicaragua, from The Dictionary of Art (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Kotler, Jared of Washington Office on Latin America. Current Situation in Nicaragua and U.S. Policy, October 29, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Human Rights Watch/Americas. Nicaragua - Separating Facts From Fiction (The Work of the Tripartite Commission in Nicaragua). October 1994, vol. VI, no. 13 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Instituto Nacional De Estadisticas Y Censos (INEC). The People of Nicaragua An Overview of the Social and Economics Conditions of Living - Results from the Standard Living Measurement Survey, First Draft, Managua, Nicaragua, October 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - United Nations Development Programme (UNDP). Statement for the Consultative Group Meeting on Nicaragua - Paris, 16-17 June 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - FSLN. Estatutos DEI FSLN, Managua, Nicaragua, May 22, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses (IEN). Resumen Ejecutivo - El FSLN: Su Dinamica Y Perspectivas Enfoque Desde La Opinion de la Base Sandinista, (Segundo insumo del IEN para el Congreso Extraordinario del FSLN) Managua, Nicaragua, May 3, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Universidad Centroamericana, Vice Rectoria de Investigacion y Post-Grado. Maestria en Relaciones Internacionales, Managua, Nicaragua, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Padre Miguel d'Escoto Brockmann. El Divisionismo De Sergio (sus ataques solapados contra el FSLN), Managua Nicaragua, March 1994 (Reflexiones del Padre Brockmann sobre declaraciones de Sergio Ramirez Mercado del 14 de Febrero al 10 de Marzo de 1994) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Conferencia Episcopal de Nicaragua. Para Avivar la Esperanza del Pueblo de Dios Carta Partoral de la Conferencia Episcopal de Nicaragua, May 1, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Conferencia Epsicopal de Nicaragua. La Religion, Sus Postulados Y Sus Manipulaciones, El FSLN Y La Iglesia, October 7, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified author, The Nicaraguan Revolution Four Years After the Sandinista Electoral Defeat (A manuscript T. Walker reviewed in 1995 for The Journal of Inter American and World Affairs) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Rosemary Radford Ruether, The Art of Survival: Feminism in the Past, Present, and Future of Nicaragua, Sojourners, July, 1993, pp. 18-21 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Hanusz, Claire M. OU Thesis on Imperialist Penetration or International Solidarity?: U.S.-Latin American Labour Relations and the case of AIFLD in Nicaragua 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses. Resumen Ejecutivo: La Gobernabilidad y el Acuerdo Nacional en Nicaragua-Auscultacion de la Opinion Publica Nicaraguense. Naciones Unidas- Grupo de apoyo-Poderes del Estado. Managua, March 14, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses. Resumen Ejecutivo de la Investigacion: LA Cultura Politica en Nicaragua-Analisis desde la auscultacion de opinion publica nacional- entrevistas intensivas y grupos focales, May 20, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Schroeder, Michael J. 'All our Family Grudges':Civil War, Imperialism, Nationalism and Popular Protest, and State Formation in the Segovias of Nicaragua, 1927-1934. Conference Rethinking the Post-Colonial Encounter:Transnational Perspectives on the United State's Presence in Latin America. Yale University, October 18-21, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Movimiento Renovador Sandinista. "Estatutos: Propuesta para Discusion.", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Isidro Tellez, Presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, July 4, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Fernando Agüero, Presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, May 18, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Francisco Samper, Coordinador General del MUR (y asesor del comité de Asuntos Económicos de la Asamblea Nacional. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, July 8, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Humberto Doña, Primer Vice Presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, July 22-23, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Virgilio Godoy, Vice Presidente de la República de Nicaragua, y Secretario del Comité Ejecutivo del PLI. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, June 8, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Bonifacio Miranda, Secretario General; Leslie Pérez Moraga, Secretario de Organización; Jorge Bendaña Tellez, Secretario de Finanzas (todos de la comisión Política del Partido). Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, June 6, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Blanca Rojas, Presidente; Giovanni D'Ciofalo, Delegado General del Partido Unionista Centroamericano. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, May 17, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Gustavo Tablada, Presidente; Salvador Súarez Miranda, Miembro de la Comisión Política. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, June 29, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Elí Altimirano, Secretario General. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, May 20-June 28, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Dr. Ricardo Vega, presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, July 28, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Eliseo Nuñez H., Vice Presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, June 28, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Roger Mendieta, Presidente; Adolfo Calero Portacarrero, Vice Presidente. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, June 27, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Adolfo José Jarquín Ortel, Presidente del Partido y diputado; González Rodríguez Reyes, vicepresidente del partido; Jorge Balladares Sirías, secretario de Organización. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, May 16-18, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Douglas Stuart H. y Kenneth M. Coleman. Entrevistas con líderes partidarios: Rodolfo Robelo H., Magistrado, Corte Suprema de Justicia y Vice Presidente, PLIUN. Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Nicaragua, July 20, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Coalicion Nacional de Mujeres, Agenda Minima. Managua, 21 pp, March 1991 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Etica y Transparencia. Observando el Proceso Electoral. Managua, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - El Derecho al Servicio de la Igualdad, 2pp (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - UN Development Program, Nicaragua 1996: Contributions to the analysis of the Pending Agenda, Washington, 14 pp, June 17-18, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - PNUD Nicaragua. Panorama Electoral Nicaragua 1996, 2 pp, May 30, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - FSLN. Documento de Acuerdos Basicos Levantando la Produccion, Trabajo y Bienestar para Todos. Managua, 5 pp, May 9, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Juntos (Revista Fundacion de ex-Combatientes de Guerra), Vol i, No 1, 33 pp (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Pablo Antonio Cuadra (Academia Nicaraguense de la Lengua) Carta a Antonio Lacayo, Managua, 2pp, June 19, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Antonio Lacayo, Palabras de Antonio Lacayo al Momento de Salir Electo como candidato... Managua, 7pp, April 21, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Proyecto Nacional. Comunicado (about the y and o problem) 1 p, June 19, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Uriel Molina Oliu, Testimonio ante el decreto de dimision de la orden de frailes menores franciscanos, 35 pp (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Rodolfo Delgado Romero, IEN, La Transicion en Nicaragua: Gobernabilidad, desarrollo, y elecciones, 19 pp, November 20, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - USAID Managua, Comunicado de Prensa: Asistencia de los Estados Unidos para las Elecciones de 1996 en Nicaragua, 2 pp, May 1996 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Jennifer McCoy (Carter Center), Statement for the House International Relations Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere, Putting the 1996 Nicaraguan Elections in Perspective, Washington, 12 pp, April 18, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - CENIDH. Informe Anual 1995: Nicaragua Derechos Humanos, Managua 136 pp, February 1996 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Organizacion Militar (The Military Code) in La Gaceta. 16 pp, September 2, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - International Republican Institute (Various documents on Nicaraguan Electoral Process), 21 pp (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - IEN/Union Europeo. Proyecto Educacion Para la Paz la Democracia y los Derechos Humanos. Documento Metodologico 23 pp Documento Base 16 pp, May 3, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - IEN/Union Europeo. Proyecto Educacion Para la Paz la Democracia y los Derechos Humanos. Documento Metodologico 23 pp Documento Base 16 pp, May 3, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Etica y Transparencia. Informe sobre inscripcion ad hoc [Ethics and Transparency. Ad hoc report on registration] (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses, Encuesta sobre la mujer nicaraguense y del ejercicio de sus derechos politicos (encuesta de hogares). Managua, Nicaragua, August 1996 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses, Encuesta de opinion publica: la gobernabilidad en Nicaragua. Managua, Nicaragua, August 1996 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Prevost, Gary. The Nicaraguan revolution-six years after the Sandinista electoral defeat. Third World Quarterly, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 71)